Nanxin Chen

Department of Zhiyuan College Shanghai Jiao Tong University 800 Dongchuan Road, Shanghai Minhang Email: bobchennan@gmail.com

Repository: http://github.com/bobchennan

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I started learning programming around 2005 and took part in several programming contests in high school and campus. Programs lead me to discover some interesting areas which I'm really interested in so I decided to major in **Computer Science and Technology**. My primary research area is **speech and natural language processing**. My broader interests include **machine learning**, and I believe that it is today's answer to tomorrow's questions.

EDUCATION

Shanghai Jiao Tong University, China B.S., Computer Science and Technology(ACM Honored Class)

Sept 2011 - Jul 2015

PUBLICATIONS & PATENTS

- Yuan Liu, Yanmin Qian, Nanxin Chen, Tianfan Fu, Ya Zhang, Kai Yu. Deep Features for Text-dependent Speaker Verification. Speech Communication, vol. 73, 1-13, 2015.
- Nanxin Chen, Yanmin Qian, Heinrich Dinkel, Bo Chen and Kai Yu, Robust Deep Feature for Spoofing Detection The SJTU system for ASVspoof 2015 challenge. 16th Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association(InterSpeech), Dresden, Germany, 2015: 2097-2101
- Nanxin Chen, Yanmin Qian and Kai Yu, Multi-Task Deep Learning For Text-dependent Speaker Verification. 16th Annual Conference of the International Speech Communication Association (InterSpeech), Dresden, Germany, 2015: 185-189
- Yanlong Wang, Nanxin Chen, Kai Yu and Weida Zhou. A voice wake method and system. CN103956164 $^{\Lambda}$
- Sibo Tong, Nanxin Chen, Yanmin Qian and Kai Yu. Evaluating VAD For Automatic Speech Recognition. 12th IEEE International Conference on Signal Processing(ICSP), Hangzhou, 2014: 2308-2314

HONORS

- 2015 Excellent College Students of *China Computer Federation(CCF)*(granted by Alexander Wolf, President of *ACM*)
- International Speech Communication Association (ISCA) grant for Interspeech 2015 (60 students worldwide)
- Rank 3 in the ASVspoof challenge 2015(28 teams worldwide)
- Xing Cai Scholarship, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2012 & 2013, awarded to only one student in each direction(totally four directions)
- Second Class Scholarship, Shanghai Jiao Tong University, 2011 & 2012, awarded to top 5% students
- ACM-International Collegiate Programming Contest(ACM-ICPC)
 - Fifth Place, The 2011 ACM-ICPC Asia Shanghai Regional Contest(Team Evolution)
 - Fifth Place, The 2011 ACM-ICPC Asia Phuket Regional Contest(Team Evolution)

SKILLS

Programming Language: Bash, Batch, C, Coq, C++, C#, Java, LATEX, LC-3, Matlab, NodeJS, R, Pascal, Python, Scala, SQL, Verilog HDL

Sports: mountain climbing, playing table tennis, playing badminton, hiking

EXPERIENCE

Hefei, China, CNCC 2015

October 2015

- Attended presentation by Michael Stonebraker, who won the 2014 ACM Turing Award
- Received CCF Excellent College Students Award from Alexander Wolf

ICD, Dresden, Interspeech 2015

September 2015

- Published 2 papers
- Received grants from International Speech Communication Association(ISCA)
- Student volunteer

Microsoft Research Asis, Full-time Intern Knowledge Mining group

August 2014 - February 2015

- Co-reference resolution system
 - Advisor: Yohn Cao, Zaiqing Nie
 - Built a co-reference resolution system which gives the coref links in passage
 - The whole systems included both learning-based system and rule-based system.

Cornell University, Summer Vacation

June 2014 - August 2014

- Attended classes given by John Hopcroft, David Gries and Michael Clarkson
- Did research on deep neural network(randomness and performance on different configurations), supervised by John Hopcroft

Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Research Assistant SpeechLab

September 2013 - Present

- Automatic Speaker Verification Spoofing Detection
 - Advisor: Yanmin Qian
 - Took part in the ASVSpoofing challenge 2015
 - Ranked 3rd(28 teams worldwide)
- Robust speaker verification using joint learning
 - Advisor: Kai Yu, Yanmin Qian
 - Built a robust speaker verification system
 - Used joint learning features given by joint deep neural network to enhance the performance of speaker verification
- Waking model for speech system
 - Advisor: Kai Yu
 - Constructed a waking system using simple body language such as claps to awake speech systems
 - Patent: A voice wake method and system

Shanghai Jiao Tong University, Teaching Assistant Class: Programming

September 2012 - January 2013

- Organized four programming lectures, four computer programming tests and related discussion lectures
- Designed a new class project(multi-player game AI) to replace old one(library management framework)